&gt;&gt; To help us with this lesson,
&gt;&gt; このレッスンを手伝ってくれる
we're excited to welcome Drew Gray,
Drew Gray氏をお迎えしています
who's leading the self-driving car team at Otto
彼は現在はUberの一部である
which is now part of Uber. Thanks for joining us Drew.
Ottoで自動運転車チームを率いています参加してくれてありがとう Drew
&gt;&gt; You're welcome.
&gt;&gt; どういたしまして
&gt;&gt; So Drew, can you tell us a little bit more about how
&gt;&gt; さて Drew もう少し詳しく
you use deep learning for self-driving cars at Otto.
Ottoでの自動運転車に関するディープラーニングの利用について話してもらえますか
&gt;&gt; For sure. Deep neural networks have been a big focus of my work at Otto.
&gt;&gt; そうですねディープニューラルネットワークはOttoでの私の仕事の中心です
We're exploring whether we can get a car to drive itself,
自動運転が可能かどうかを探っているのですが
using only deep neural networks and nothing else.
それにはディープニューラルネットワークだけを使用し 他には何も使用していません
Sometimes we call that behavioral cloning
それを行動クローニングと呼ぶこともあります
because you're training the network that clone human driving behavior.
人間の運転行動をクローンするネットワークをトレーニングしているからです
Well, sometimes it's called end-to-end learning because the network
また エンドツーエンドラーニングと呼ばれることもあります
is learning to predict the correct steering angle and speed,
ネットワークはセンサーからの入力だけを使用して
using only the inputs from the sensors.
正しいステアリング角度と速度を予測することを学習するからです
&gt;&gt; So as I understand it, deep learning isn't
&gt;&gt; 私が理解している限りではディープラーニングは
the only approach to building a self-driving car.
自動運転車を作るための唯一のアプローチではありません
For a number of years, people have been working on
長年 人々は より伝統的な種類の
a more traditional sort of robotics approach.
ロボット工学アプローチに取り組んできました
So, why go with deep learning over robotics approach?
では なぜロボット工学アプローチよりディープラーニングなのでしょうか
&gt;&gt; Right. Well, my Ph.D. is actually in control theory and artificial intelligence.
&gt;&gt; そのとおりです私の博士号は実際には制御理論と人工知能におけるものです
So, I spent a lot of time working on both approaches.
そこで私は多くの時間を両方のアプローチに費やしてきました
In fact, engineers at Otto are working on
実際 Ottoのエンジニアはディープラーニングと
both deep learning and the standard robotics approach.
標準的ロボット工学アプローチの両方に取り組んでいます
I'm working on deep learning because I think it has the potential to
私がディープラーニングに取り組んでいるのは 自動運転車の開発方法を
fundamentally change how we develop self-driving cars.
根本から変える可能性があると思っているからです
&gt;&gt; Cool. Can you explain a little bit more about
&gt;&gt; すごいですもう少し詳しく
the difference between the deep learning approach versus the robotics approach.
ディープラーニングアプローチとロボット工学アプローチの違いについて説明してもらえますか
&gt;&gt; The robotics approach in building self-driving cars involves a lot
&gt;&gt; ロボット工学アプローチによる自動運転車の構築には
of detail knowledge about sensors, controls and planning.
センサー 制御 およびプランニングに関する多くの詳細な知識が必要です
With the deep learning approach,
ディープラーニングアプローチでは
we don't have to program all that detail knowledge into the vehicle.
詳細な知識を車両にプログラミングする必要はありません
We simply feed all the information we have into the network,
ただ 持てる情報のすべてをネットワークに与えて
and then we let the network figure out on its own what's important.
ネットワークにとって何が重要かをネットワーク自身に見つけさせます
Also, deep learning allows us to build a feedback loop where the more we drive,
また ディープラーニングではフィードバックループを作ることができ 運転すればするほど
the more data we can collect,
より多くのデータを収集でき
which in turn allows us to learn how to drive even better.
より良い運転方法を学ぶことができます
&gt;&gt; So, what you're doing sounds pretty similar to what
&gt;&gt; あなたがしていることは学生がこのモジュールの最後の
students will be doing in their final project at the end of this module,
最終的なプロジェクトで行うことと かなり似ているようですね
only they'll be implementing behavioral cloning and simulator.
学生が実装するのは行動クローニングとシミュレーターですが
&gt;&gt; Well, a simulator certainly makes things easier,
&gt;&gt; ええ シミュレーターは確かに物事を簡単にしてくれますが
but the overarching principles are the
シミュレーターでも実際の車でも
same whether you're in the simulator or a real vehicle.
全体的な原理は同じです
&gt;&gt; Yeah, but can you actually drive a real vehicle with just a deep neural network?
&gt;&gt; なるほど  でもディープニューラルネットワークだけで実際の車を運転できますか
&gt;&gt; You can. We actually recently drove 20 miles
&gt;&gt;できます実際 最近 サンフランシスコから
down the highway in San Francisco to the airport and back,
空港までの高速道路の往復20マイルを
without touching the steering wheel once.
一度もハンドルに触らずに運転しました
&gt;&gt; Wow. So it really works.
&gt;&gt; 驚きです本当にできるのですね
Well then, let's get started building a deep neural network.
では ディープニューラルネットワークの構築を始めましょう
&gt;&gt; Let's do it.
&gt;&gt; 早速始めましょう